Guide to the General Frederick Steele Papers, 1845-1965 (inclusive), 1862-1868 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
- Series IA. Correspondence and papers of General Frederick Steele, 1845-1890.
  - Correspondence 1865, October 4-13. (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - 9. 1865, Oct. 10.37th Illinois Veteran Volunteer Infantry. Tri-monthly Report. DS of R. Kennicott and C. B. Chroniger.
    - 10. 1865, Oct. 10.24th Battalion Indiana Infantry Veteran Volunteers. Tri-monthly Report. DS of Wm. S. Pollard and J. P. McCart.
    - 11. 1865, Oct. 11.Division of the Gulf. S.O. No. 76, extract 7. Printed, s. Robt. Adams, Jr. FS's leave cancelled, to go to Ft. Vancouver.
    - 12. 1865, Oct. 12.[J. L.] Lyon to FS. ALS.
    - 13. 1865, Oct. 12.[Luis] Robles to FS. ANS in Spanish. Encloses note of Mr. Masson.
    - 14. 1865, Oct. 12.H. G. Wright to FS. ALS. Re: Stanley, Whittelsey.
    - 15. [1865, Oct. 13?].FS to Andrew Johnson. ADfS of tel. Re: Isaac Surratt, assassination plot.
    - 16. 1865, Oct. 13.FS to P. H. Sheridan. Copy by Richard Kent. Sending dispatches re: Suratt, Cortina's attack on Mejia, Escobedo has received a message from Juarez about Cortina, advocates helping Liberals, injustice.
  - Correspondence 1865, October 17-31. (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - 1. 1865, Oct. 17.[Tomas Nejia] to FS. Letter in Spanish. The firing from a Mexican house on the Brownsville hospital. Not signed.
    - 2a. and 2b. 1865, Oct. 19.M[ariano] Escobedo to W. R. [sic] Steele (FS). ANS in Spanish and translation. Personal, coming to Matamoros.
    - 3. 1865, Oct. 19.Giles A. Smith to FS. Xeros of LS. Appreciation.
    - 4-5. 1865, Oct. 20.M[ariano] Escobedo to W. R. [sic] S. [ALS] in Spanish and translation. To begin military operations against Matamoros.
    - 6. 1865, Oct. 20.Western District of Texas. G.O. No. 7. Printed. FS relinquishes command.
    - 7. 1865, Oct. 24.G. Garcia et al. to FS. DS in Spanish, signed by members of the Junta Patriotica Mejicana of Brownsville (G. Garcia, Andres Trevino, Man. Saavedral, [?] C. [Boria?], Francisco Gonzales Rodriguez, Alonso Aspi, Juan Francisco Dominguez, Miguel [Tovar], Antonio Zertucha, Francisco de Leon). Thanks FS for his sympathy, justice, hope for armistice.
    - 8. 1865, Oct. 27.F. J. Herron to A. C. Graham. ALS. Introduces FS.
    - 9. 1865, Oct. 31.John B. Steele to [FS]. ALS. Talked to U.S. Grant, FS incurred hostility of Radicals, personal advice, FS's promotion.
  - Correspondence 1865, November. (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - 1a. 1865, Nov. 14.George Steele to Dear Brother. Xerox of ALS.
    - 1b. 1865, Nov. 15.A. P. Wood to FS. ALS. Writing military history of Iowa, wants FS's record since Colonelcy of 8th Iowa Infantry.
    - 2. 1865, Nov. [16]William B. Astor et al. Printed invitation to Grant Reception on 20th.
    - 3. [1865, Nov. 20].Grant Reception. Printed admission ticket.
    - 4. [1865, Nov. 20].Grant Reception. Printed dinner ticket.
  - Correspondence 1865, December. (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - 1. 1865, Dec. 6.Brewster & Co. (N.Y.) to FS. Receipted bill for carriage.
    - 2-3. [1865, Dec. 6].Brewster & Co. Lithographs of 2 carriages.
    - 4. 1865, Dec. 9.Headquarters of the Army - A.G.O. S.O. No. 32, extract 1. DS of [R?] Williams. FS may delay going to Dept. of the Columbia.
    - 5. 1865, Dec. 17.W. D. Snow to FS. ALS. Re: Pine Bluff telegraph line.
    - 6. 1865, Dec. [18?].J. W. Nesmith to H[arvey] Hadley. ALS. Introducing FS to a great Horse man.
    - 7. 1865, Dec. 19.Jas. Totten to FS. ALS. Wants recommend for brevet rank.
    - 8. 1865, Dec. 23.H. W. Halleck to E. R. S. Canby. Circular letter, s. C. T. Christensen. Difficulty with Spanish minister Tassara.
    - 9. 1865, Dec. 30.Edw. McK. Hudson to FS. ALS. Recommends Cosmopolitan Hotel in San Francisco.
    - 10. [1865].Alabama River Landings. Holograph list, unsigned.
    - 11-12. [1865].Ambros & Segura to FS. ALS in Spanish and translation. Situation in Mexico, refugees, El Republicano wants payment.
    - 13. [1865,].Army and Division of West Mississippi. G.F.O. No. 12. ADS of C. T. Christensen. Casualty reports.
    - 14. [1865].G. [Baturoni]. Justice. Holograph article. Troubles of Mexican editors, imprisonment of D. W. T. Claveran.
    - 15. [1865].C. T. Christensen to FS. Tel. Mme. Kenner's plantation (Oakland).
    - 16. [1865].11th Illinois Volunteer Infantry. Roster of Commissioned Officers. ADS of James H. Coates.
    - 17. [1865].1st Division, U.S. Colored Troops et al. List of Regiments, etc. Unsigned.
    - 18. [1865].1st Light Battery Indiana Volunteers. Roster of Commissioned Officers. ADS of Lawrence Jacoby.
    - 19a. and 19b. [1865].47th Regiment Indiana Veteran Volunteer Infantry. Report and Roster of Commissioned Officers. DS of Sextus H. Shearer.
    - 20a. [1865].Madam [Levirt] to FS. ALS.
    - 20b. [1865].W. T. House to [J. F.] Lacey. Tel. or signal.
    - 21. [1865].2nd Connecticut Light Battery. Roster of Commissioned Officers. DS of Walter S. Hotchkiss.
    - 22. [1865].7th Battery Massachusetts Light Artillery. Roster of Commissioned Officers. ADS of N. W. Storer.
    - 23. [1865].[FS] to P. H. Sheridan. ADf. Gov. DeLeon, Cortina, Escobedo, Juarez, Trevino, rebel Parsons.
    - 24. [1865].34th Indiana Veteran Volunteer Infantry. Report of Strength. DS of Nimrod Headington.
    - 25. [1865].37th Illinois Infantry. Roster of Commissioned Officers. ADS of Herman Wolferd.
    - 26. [1865].28th Regiment Illinois Infantry. Report. ADS of Hinman Rhodes.
    - 27. [1865].U.S. Forces, Barrancas, Fla. Consolidated Tri-Monthly Field Return. AD.
    - 28-30. [1865].Unknown. [FS?] Holograph quotations re: treaties, especially with regard to Mexico.
  - Correspondence 1866, January-April. (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - 1. 1866, Jan. 4.J. Bidwell to C. J. Brenham. Copy. Re: John Adair, Jr.
    - 2a. 1866, Jan. 24.Ben. H. Brooks to FS. ALS. Family.
    - 2b. 1866, Jan. 24.D. Strong to FS. Tel. Lt. Strong left by Steamer Atlantic on the 11th.
    - 3. 1866, Jan. 25.Ben. H. Brooks to FS. ALS. Personal.
    - 4. 1866, Feb. 5.[?] M. Heuston to FS. ADS. Bill for sale of horse Belle.
    - 5. 1866, Feb. 13.C. J. Brenham to John Adair. ALS. Re: Adair' son. See #1.
    - 6. 1866, Feb. 16.[R. C. Drune?] to FS. ANS. Invitation to visit Hayward and Easton ranches.
    - 7. 1866, Feb. 24.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 4. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. FS assumes command, staff.
    - 8. 1866, Mar. 2.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 5. Printed. s. Geo. Williams. Boise becomes District under Marshall.
    - 9. 1866, Mar. 5.C. C. Andrews to FS. ALS. Wants to be recommended as Col. of one of new regiments.
    - 10. 1866, [Jan. 16].C. C. Andrews. Printed military record. Enclosed in #9.
    - 11. 1866, Mar. 5.Robt. N. Scott to FS. ALS. Re: salute at San Francisco. Puget Sound, Port Townsend, troops on San Juan Island.
    - 12. 1866, Mar. 27.John B. Steele to [FS]. ALS. Personal, FS's position and career, flare-up between radicals and President.
    - 13. 1866, Apr. 4.H. W. Halleck to FS. Copy s. Robert N. Scott. Cavalry, Indian trouble in Goose and Surprise Valleys, general instructions re: Indians, treaties a fraud.
    - 14. 1866, Apr. 5.John B. Steele to FS. ALS. Will send field desk.
    - 15. 1866, Apr. 20.William d Pickering to FS. ALS. Gov's. welcome, wants inspection of military posts on Puget Sound.
    - 16. 1866, Apr. 27.Addison C. Gibbs to FS. ALS. Gov. of Ore. wants muster-out of Oregon volunteers.
  - Correspondence 1866, May-July. (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - 1. 1866, May 6.A. C. Gibbs to FS. ALS. Politics involved in muster-out of Ore. volunteers.
    - 2. 1866, May 6.C. G. Sawtelle to FS. ALS. One of FS's horses to be sold, Cap, partridge shooting, etc.
    - 3. 1866, May 10.D. W. Ballard to FS. ALS. Political emergency in Ore., Nez Perce restless over delay in payment of annuities. Concurrence s. Thos. Monreith, Walter Monreith, Edward R. Geary, W. A. McPherson, Dennis Bench.
    - 4. 1866, Jun. 2.Quartermaster General's Office to FS. Acknowledgement form--receipt of returns, etc. Stamp of Alex. J. Perry.
    - 5. 1866, Jun. 4.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 7. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Re: Lt. Richard P. Strong.
    - 6. 1866, Jun. 15.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 8. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Re: medical supplies.
    - 7. 1866, Jun. 23.[George] Stoneman to FS. ALS. Sends clip that could be slanderous.
    - 8. 1866, Jul. 14.H. W. Halleck to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Ft. Boise useless as a military post, operation in Owyhee Mountains, Indians--Winnemucca and Daulina of Piutes.
    - 9. 1866, Jul. 17.Charles S. McEntee to FS. ALS. Personal.
    - 10. 1866, Jul. 26.Orville Jennings to FS. ALS. Asks about Cregon country.
    - 11. 1866, Jul. 27.FS to George Steele. ALS. Inspection tour, visit to Victoria, travel through Oregon, Indian trouble.
  - Correspondence 1866, August-October. (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - 1. 1866, Aug. 7.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 9. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. FS's staff, commendations.
    - 2. 1866, Aug. 7.George Steele to FS. ALS. Personal, brothers purchased ranch in San Luis obispo.
    - 3. 1866, Aug. 16.Edwin M. Stanton to FS. Printed LS. Appoints FS Colonel 20th Infantry Regiment.
    - 4. 1866, Aug. 17.O. E. Babcock to FS. Tel. Halleck wants to retain FS at brevet rank, part of poem on verso.
    - 5. 1866, Aug. 27.FS to Geo. Steele. ALS. Possibility of striking oil at San Luis Obispo. Pope to command Dept. of the Columbia.
    - 6. 1866, Aug. 30.J. W. [Turner] to __. Taylor. ALS. Introduces Maj. Macomber.
    - 7. 1866, Sept. 14.Robt. N. Scott to FS. ALS. Re: Pope, etc.
    - 8. 1866, Sept. 14.I. C. Steele to FS. ALS. Family news, the ranch.
    - 9a. 1866, Sept. 17.FS and Rufus Ingalls to J. H. [sic] Nesmith. ALS. Asks favor for Hazard Stevens.
    - 9b. [1866, Sept. 24].James O'Hara to FS. ALS. and cover. Death of John B. Steele.
    - 10. 1866, Oct. 5.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 10. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. W. I. Sanborn.
    - 11. 1866, Oct. 6.FS to Adjutant General, U.S. Army. ANS. Accepts appointment as Colonel.
    - 12. 1866, Oct. 8.John Adair to FS. ALS. RE: Adair's son.
    - 13. 1866, Oct. 19.Geo. Steele to FS. ALS. Death of John B. Steele.
    - 14. 1866, Oct. 30.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 11. Printed s. Richard P. Strong. Staff changes.
    - 15. 1866, Oct. 31.Charles S. McEntee to FS. ALS. Re: FS's rank and position.
  - Correspondence 1866, November. (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - 1. 1866, Nov. 1.[R. N.] Scott to FS. ALS. Pope given 6 mos. leave.
    - 2. 1866, Nov. 8.R. P. Strong to[FS]. ALS. Trip to San Francisco, Marshall, Portland Headquarters, Custer Lt. Colonel of 8th Cavalry, Miss Banks.
    - 3. 1866, Nov. 9.Rufus Ingalls to FS. ALS. Personal, Portland Headquarters, Grant, disappointing new ranks.
    - 4. 1866, Nov. 15.Dept. of California. G.O. No. 44. Printed. Military Districts in Arizona-California.
    - 5. 1866, Nov. 15.Quartermaster General's Office - Property Div. Printed acknowledgement, receipt of returns, stamp of Chs. Thomas.
    - 6. 1866, Nov. 15.Robt. N. Scott to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Quartermaster contracts at FT. Boise.
    - 7. 1866, Nov. 16.E. B. Babbitt to FS. ALS. To go to Dept. of the Columbia.
    - 8. 1866, Nov. 19.R. P. Strong to FS. ALS. Movement of Dept. of the Columbia Headquarters to Portland, personal, Miss Banks.
    - 9. 1866, Nov. 22.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 12. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Staff appointments.
    - 10. 1866, Nov. 22.John McCracken et al. to FS. ANS. Invitation to party. Also s. E. I. DeHart, Lloyd Brooke, Edwin Russell.
    - 11. 1866, Nov. 22.R. P. Strong to FS. ALS. Personal, army news.
    - 12. 1866, Nov. 24.Quartermaster General's Office. Printed acknowledgement form, stamp of Chs. Thomas.
    - 13. 1866, Nov. 24.R. P. Strong. to FS. ALS.
    - 14. 1866, Nov. 30.Robt. N. Scott to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Contracts, supplies, etc.
  - Correspondence 1866, December. (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - 1. 1866, Dec. 2.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 13. Printed. Treasury Dept. Circular--taxes, rations.
    - 1b. [1866] Dec 5 #14 folder 86
    - 2. 1866, Dec. 7.William Pickering to FS. ALS. E. V. Turner.
    - 3. 1866, Dec. 12.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 14. Printed. Staff changes.
    - 4. 1866, Dec. 21.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 15. Printed, s. George Macomber. Re: Civilian employees.
    - 5. 1866, Dec. 28.War Department - A.G.O. S.O. No. 643, extract 11, Printed, stamped E. D. Townsend. FS to report to San Francisco for examination.
    - 6. 1866, Dec. 29.Henry C. Hodges to J. F. Rusling. Copy s. H. C. Hodges. Reply to insolent letter.
    - 7. 1866, Dec. 29.Henry C. Hodges to FS. ANS.
    - 8. 1866, Dec. 31.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 16. Printed, s. George Macomber. Court martial.
    - 9. 1866,DDept. of the Columbia. Printed Index of General Orders.
  - Correspondence 1867, January 1-11. (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - 1. 1867, Jan.1.Dept. of the Columbia. Printed Circular No. 1, s. George Macomber. Roster of Troops.
    - 2. 1867, Jan. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 1. Printed, s. George Macomber. Commendations for actions against Indians.
    - 3. 1867, Jan. 3.Jos. Lyman to FS. ALS. Personal, refers to Rio Grande, death of Gen. Curtis, railroad.
    - 4. 1867, Jan. 4.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. District of Boise, extravagance.
    - 5. 1867, Jan. 11.E. B. Babbitt to FS. ALS with copy of letter Dec. 31, 1866, Theodore J. Edkerson to E. B. Babbitt. Fort Boise's debts.
    - 6. 1867, Jan. 11.FS to James B. Fry. Copy s. Richard. Strong. Marshall's disobedience.
  - Correspondence 1867, January 12-March. (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - 1. 1867, Jan. 12.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Inspection of FT. Boise.
    - 2. 1867, Jan. 15.E. D. Townsend to FS. NS. FS mustered out of Volunteer Service as Major General as of Mar. 1, 1867.
    - 3. 1867, Jan. 20.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 2. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial.
    - 4. 1867, Jan. 25.[A. C. M. Pennington] to FS. ALS. Time and date of exam.
    - 5. 1867, Jan. 26.[Wm. H. French] to FS. ANS. Exam passes FS as qualified for Colonel's commission.
    - 6. 1867, Jan. 31.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 3. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Transfer of Headquarters from Ft. Vancouver to Portland.
    - 7. 1867, Feb. 21.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 4. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Cases Tried by General Court Martial.
    - 8. 1867, Mar. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. Printed Circular No. 3, s. Geo. Williams. Roster of Troops.
    - 9. 1867, Mar. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 5. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Staff changes.
    - 10. 1867, Mar. 16.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 6, Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Sentences for desertion.
    - 11. 1867, Mar. 17.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 7. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Distribution of War Dept. General Orders.
    - 12. 1867, Mar. 23.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 8. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Inspections of property.
    - 13. 1867, Mar. 25.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 9. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Staff changes.
  - Correspondence 1867, April-May. (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - 1. 1867, Apr. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. Printed Circular No. 4, s. Geo. Williams. Roster of troops.
    - 2. 1867, Apr. 3.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 10. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial cases.
    - 3., 4a. and 4b. 1867, Apr. 5.Hawthorne Theatricals. Printed invitation, ticket and cover.
    - 5. 1867, Apr. 6.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 11. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial cases.
    - 6. 1867, Apr. 6.A. Hayward to FS. ANS.
    - 7. 1867, Apr. 16.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 12. Printed, s. George Macomber. Court martial.
    - 8. 1867, Apr. 17.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 13. Printed, s. George Macomber. Tri-monthly Post returns, enlisted men must be single and 55.
    - 9. 1867, Apr. 20.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 14. Printed, s. George Macomber. Court martial.
    - 10. 1867, Apr. 25.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 15. Printed s. George Macomber. Officers report on arrival, harboring deserters.
    - 11. 1867, Apr. 26.[FS] to Geo. Crook. Letter, unsigned. Moving Camp Warner, help of reservation Indians.
    - 12. 1867, Apr. 29.Headquarters of the Army - A.G.O. S.O. No. 219, extract 2. Printed, stamped E. D. Townsend. Relieve FS at Columbia, 6 month leave.
    - 13. 1867, May 9.Associated Alumni of the Pacific Coast. Printed announcement of 4th Annual Meeting in Oakland, Bret Harte, poet.
    - 14. 1867, May 18.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 16. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial.
    - 15. 1867, May 23.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 17. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial of Capt. Weldy.
  - Correspondence 1867, June. (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - 1. 1867, Jun. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 18. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial.
    - 2. 1867, Jun. 6.G. W. Schofield to FS. ALS. Re: sale of horse, Rousseau may or may not go West.
    - 3. 1867, Jun. 7.H. W. Corbett and Geo. H. Williams to E. M. Stanton. ANS. Asking to have FS continued in command of District of Oregon.
    - 4. 1867, Jun. 15.Dept. of the Columbia. Printed Circular No. 6, s. Geo. Williams. Roster of troops.
    - 5. 1867, Jun. 15.Treasury Department. to FS. Printed form letter s. W. P. [Shearman?].
    - 6. 1867, Jun. 16.George Crook to FS. ALS. Camp C. F. Smith in Oregon, Silver River Country, Indians.
    - 7. 1867, Jun. 18.Chas. A. Whittier to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Mules hired, contracts.
    - 8. 1867, Jun. 19.Robt. N. Scott to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Price for pack mules.
    - 9. 1867, Jun. 22.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 19. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Staff changes.
    - 10. 1867, Jun. 24.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 20. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial.
    - 11. 1867, Jun. 25.FS to R. N. Scott. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Whittier's report incorrect.
  - Correspondence 1867, July. (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - 1. 1867, Jul. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 21. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. July 4 instructions.
    - 2. 1867, Jul. 1.James B. Fry to FS. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong. Contract or purchase of transport.
    - 3. 1867, Jul. 1.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Contracts not forwarded.
    - 4. 1867, Jul. 1.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 5. 1867, Jul. 1.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Duties of Inspectors.
    - 6. 1867, Jul. 3.Dept. of the Columbia. Printed Circular No. 7, s. Geo. Williams. Clerks, officeds should make out own papers.
    - 7. 1867, Jul. 25.[D. H. Rucker?] to FS. LS. FS's account for court martial service 1858-59.
  - Correspondence 1867, August. (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - 1. 1867, Aug. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 22. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial.
    - 2. 1867, Aug. 5.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Re: Whittier.
    - 3. 1867, Aug. 13.U. S. Grant to FS. ALS. use no political influence to obtain promotion... wait on Pacific Coant for a time. [Located in safe].
    - 4. 1867, Aug. 15.Dept. of the Columbia. Printed Circular No. 8, s. Geo. Williams. Roster.
    - 5. 1867, Aug. 24.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Opposition to Crook's wish to assign Camps Watson and Logan to District of the Lakes.
    - 6. 1867, Aug. 26.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 23. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Lists of prisoners, reports of scouts and expeditions.
    - 7. 1867, Aug. 27.Robt. N. Scott to FS. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong. New contracts.
    - 8. 1867, Aug. 29.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. 1st Cavalry, division of District of Owyhee.
    - 9. 1867, Aug. 30.Richard P. Strong to E. B. Babbitt. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Supply of grain, etc.
    - 10. 1867, Aug. 31.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 24. Printed s. Geo. Williams. Report of animals.
  - Correspondence 1867, September 2-20. (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - 1. 1867, Sept. 2.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 25. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Court martial cases.
    - 2. 1867, Sept. 14.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 26. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Establishment of new posts in Oregon.
    - 3. 1867, Sept. 16.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 27. Printed s. Geo. Williams. Court martial at Camp Steele, San Juan Island.
    - 4. 1867, Sept. 17.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong. Withdraws approval of freight contracts for new posts.
    - 5. 1867, Sept. 17.Joseph Teal to FS. LS. Statement that contractors charged unreasonable amount.
    - 6. 1867, Sept. 17.Official copy of #5, s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 7. 1867, Sept. 18.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 28. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Reduce expenditures.
    - 8. 1867, Sept. 19.FS to H. W. Halleck. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong. Contracts a swindle.
    - 9. 1867, Sept. 19.Richard P. Strong to E. B. Babbitt. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. To get new contract.
    - 10. 1867, Sept. 19.Richard P. Strong to E. B. Babbitt. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Bidding.
    - 11. 1867, Sept. 20.Benj. F. Goodwin. Statement. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Took deposition from Teal
    - 12. 1867, Sept. 20.J. Oppenheimer to FS. LS. Denies swindle, asks for hearing.
    - 13. 1867, Sept. 20.J. Oppenheimer and J. R. Robbins. DS. Depositions notarized and s. Benj. F. Goodwin.
    - 14. 1867, Sept. 20.Official copy of #13 s. Richard P. Strong.
  - Correspondence 1867, September 21-30. (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - 1. 1867, Sept. 21.James Crawford. DS. Affidavit s. by notary W. S. Caldwell.
    - 2. 1867, Sept. 21.Official copy of #1, s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 3. 1867, Sept. 21.James B. Fry to FS. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong. Halleck calls for new bids.
    - 4. 1867, Sept. 21.James B. Fry. to FS. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 5. 1867, Sept. 21.B. Goldsmith. DS. Affidavit notarized by W. S. Caldwell.
    - 6. 1867, Sept. 21.Official copy of #5, s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 7. 1867, Sept. 21.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Contract already let.
    - 8. 1867, Sept. 21.Richard P. Strong to E. B. Babbitt. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Contract cancelled, advertising for new bids.
    - 9. 1867, Sept. 23.Joseph Teal to FS. LS. Learns of cancellation of contract--has already started to fulfill it.
    - 10. 1867, Sept. 25.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 11. 1867, Sept. 25.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Explains entire contract case.
    - 12. 1867, Sept. 26.Jas. B. Fry to FS. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 13. 1867, Sept. 26.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. New camps.
    - 14. 1867, Sept. 27.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 15. 1867, Sept. 30.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Crook's plans for winter campaign.
  - Correspondence 1867, October. (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - 1. 1867, Oct. 1.Dept. of the Columbia. Printed Circular No. 9, s. Geo. Williams. Roster.
    - 2. 1867, Oct. 1.James B. Fry to FS. Copy tel. s. Richard P. Strong. Teal contract disapproved.
    - 3. 1867, Oct. 1.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 4. 1867, Oct. 2.James B. Fry to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong.
    - 5. 1867, Oct. 3.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 29. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Employment of discharged officers and soldiers, civilian employees.
    - 6. 1867, Oct. 4.FS to Rob't. Allen. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Re: contract.
    - 7. 1867, Oct. 14.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 30. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Staff change.
    - 8. 1867, Oct. 15.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Indian risings in Oregon, citizens want to call up volunteers.
    - 9. 1867, Oct. 16.Dept. of the Columbia. G.O. No. 31. Printed, s. Geo. Williams. Vouchers.
    - 10. 1867, Oct. 24.Robt. Allen to FS. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Teal contract views.
    - 11. 1867, Oct. 25.FS to J. B. Fry. Copy s. Richard P. Strong. Supplies and equipment for District of the Lakes.
    - 12. 1867, Oct. 28.James A. Waters. ADS. Statement of his military history.